504. 435. 4678 ~ emilygdavies42@gmail.com ~ www.linkedin.com/in/emily-davies9/ ~ https://github.com/Scaramouche9

Summary

Data analyst with over 10 years of experience leveraging Excel to inform purchasing decisions, generate client leads, and track budgets. Increased ticket resolution rate by 5%, reduced equipment purchases by 10%, and generated over 50 leads. Orchestrated profitable tours with performances at over 100 venues.

Employment

Java Consultant, Genesis10: Technology Consulting Firm; Remote – 2022-2023

- Developed 9 full-stack and back-end applications using SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java, JavaScript, and React
- Tested code thoroughly using Spring Boot unit testing and developer tools to eliminate errors

Store Manager, Hollywood Lights: Audiovisual and Theatrical Retailer; Portland, OR - 2022

- Managed storefront, website, and inventory for multi-million dollar commercial lighting and sound retailer
- Drew insights from previous sales data to eliminate unnecessary spending by 10% in 3 months
- Communicated with vendors to negotiate optimal price points

Owner and member of band, Renshaw Davies; New Orleans, LA – 2012-2021

- Orchestrated booking and promotion of up to three month long tours throughout US and Canada
- Coordinated with over 100 venue owners and bands to secure successful performances
- Researched, budgeted, and purchased PA system for live performances with two vocal mics, guitar amp, and up to five digital interfaces

Office Assistant, mumms Software: Hospice and Palliative Care Solutions; New Orleans, LA – 2019-2020

- Utilized Jira to effectively resolve client tickets or dispatch to the appropriate help desk
- Conducted research and logged contact data for over 50 hospices using Excel to support lead generation

Audiovisual Technician, New Orleans Convention Center; New Orleans, LA – 2012-2019

- Conducted inventory of 18 storage rooms using Excel to inform new equipment purchases
- Provided reliable support for over 400 shows, troubleshooting audiovisual equipment to ensure client satisfaction
- Trained over 50 new and temporary employees to operate and run our equipment

Certifications

IBM Data Analyst Professional Certificate; Coursera, 2023
-Python, SQL, Excel, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Cognos

Project

Natural Disaster Tracker

- Assessing whether the frequency of 4 common types of natural disasters at different magnitudes is higher or lower than expected in a given year
- Working independently to extract, clean, analyze, and visualize data from Kaggle.com: <u>"All Natural Disasters</u> 1900-2021/EOSDIS"
- Implementing VSCode, Jupiter Notebooks, Python (Pandas), SQL, and Tableau
- Links: Tableau / Github

Education

Goucher College; Towson, MD – BA Music